<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>How To on Loknath&#39;s Log</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/tags/how-to/</link>
    <description>Recent content in How To on Loknath&#39;s Log</description>
    <image>
      <title>Loknath&#39;s Log</title>
      <url>http://localhost:1313/images/cover.png</url>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/images/cover.png</link>
    </image>
    <generator>Hugo -- 0.152.2</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 13 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/tags/how-to/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Set up SSL for SolrCloud</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/set-up-ssl-for-solrcloud/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 13 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/set-up-ssl-for-solrcloud/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;As I am highly dependent on official documentation, I found that Apache Solr maintain an awesome documentation from which I learned a lot. Setting up SSL can be found &lt;a href=&#34;https://solr.apache.org/guide/solr/latest/deployment-guide/enabling-ssl.html&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;. I am writing this for easier step by step setup.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Happy Searching!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;generate-certificate--key&#34;&gt;Generate certificate &amp;amp; key&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;From the official documentation, you can generate a self-signed certificate to test your setup. But for the trusted authority, generate a certificate and convert it to &lt;code&gt;.pfx&lt;/code&gt; format, which is type &lt;code&gt;PKCS12&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Setting Up SolrCloud for Production</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/set-up-solrcloud-for-production/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 28 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/set-up-solrcloud-for-production/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I wasn&amp;rsquo;t familiar with SolrCloud when I started working with this. When I started to learn it and working directly with it - I had done so many mistakes. Even setting up SolrCloud for production was a hassle for me (&lt;em&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m a slow learner&lt;/em&gt;). But overtime, I got a hang of it and I think writing an up-to-date guide to set up SolrCloud on production server is a good idea.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Making custom badges using shields.io</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/custom-badges-github-profile/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 18 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/custom-badges-github-profile/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;When I wanted to customize my GitHub profile, I visited many developers&amp;rsquo; GitHub profiles. I saw some badges which seemed cool to me. When I looked at the code behind the shapes, I didn&amp;rsquo;t know what was happening. Later, I tried to copy some of the code and paste them into my code, but it couldn&amp;rsquo;t solve the need.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After some reading and searching, I understood how to make them. I am writing this post as a reference so that one can understand how to make those badges, including me.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Setting up Codeblocks with Freeglut on Linux</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/codeblocks-with-freeglut-linux/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 06 Feb 2021 01:34:53 +0600</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/codeblocks-with-freeglut-linux/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In my Computer Graphics class, the teacher asked us to setup Codeblocks for the glut. She gave us a tutorial on how to setup Codeblocks on windows but didn&amp;rsquo;t provide any suggestion to set up on Linux. After some searching on google, I was able to setup Codeblocks with &lt;strong&gt;Freeglut&lt;/strong&gt; (&lt;em&gt;which is an alternative to Glut and available on Linux&lt;/em&gt;). This is a kind of writeup (&lt;em&gt;or tutorial&lt;/em&gt;) on how I was able to setup Codeblocks with Freeglut.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
